Chris Minassian

Summary

(818) 438-0340 • Cminassian@live.com, ChrisMinassian.com

Skilled therapist with varied background in psychological treatments and processes, specializing in individual therapy, facilitating groups, working with children, adolescents, and adults.

Knowledge Specialties

Developmental Psychology, Abnormal Psychology, Psychological Aspects of Parenthood, Marriage and Family Therapy, Child Development Activities

Education

Master of Arts Degree in Marriage & Family Therapy Pacific Oaks College – Pasadena, CA

Bachelor of Arts in Psychology & Bachelor of Arts in Child Development Cal State University, Northridge – Northridge, CA

Experience:

- Haynes Family of Programs 09/2015 Present
- *Individual Therapist* Providing in-home therapy to individuals (including children and adolescents). Implementing treatment plans to reach client goals, Interfacing with family to ensure ongoing client outcomes
 - Private Practice Therapist 05/2015 Present Providing intensive, short- and long-term individual and family therapy with children, adolescents, and adults diagnosed with a variety of disorders, using a variety of theoretical perspectives
 - Performing intake assessments, client evaluations, and provided diagnoses; formulates a plan of treatment to promote development and maintenance of individual goals designed to facilitate individual growth, improved social interaction, ability to manage mental illness

and live independently

- Regularly assessing and monitoring condition of client to evaluate success of treatment and adapted interventions as needed.
- Providing comprehensive case management to include referral and links to community support services, psychiatrist, medical care, housing, and social activity groups.
- Developing training curricula for colleagues and teaching workshops on psychology theories and best practices

Developmental Dynamo, Inc.

Behaviorial Interventionist/Supervisor:

12/2015 - Present

- Working one-on-one with autistic children to implement behavior management techniques
- Helping clients reach goals as designated from their individualized education plan
- Working closely with teacher and patient's care team to ensure client's progress
- Supervising Behavioral interventionists to implement company policies and interventions to help clients improve behaviors including (eloping, biting, aggression, anger, and verbal outburst.)

Phillips Graduate Institute 07/2015

Teaching Guest Lecturer - PSY 603- Counseling the Chemically Dependent and their Families

- Taught counseling the chemically dependent and their families
- Provided a curriculum for graduate students on the effects of alcoholism

and the dependent and the family

• Facilitated a group activity to enforce learning

Palo Verde College 04/2015-12/2016

Academic Counselor

- Discussing career and educational goals with students.
- Aiding in the course selection process to ensure progress towards student goals.
- Displaying an interest in student development.
- Identifying student strengths and weaknesses.
- Maintaining updated reports on student progress.
- Intervening if behavioral or academic abnormalities occur.
- Connecting students with resources, such as counselors or tutors.
- Demonstrate a strong understanding of institutional policies.
- Maintaining professional standards to aide students in achieving their goals.
- Discussing with students alternative options for careers and helping them make the best choices for their college careers.

• Pierce College 02/2013-02/2015

- Teaching Guest Lecturer
- Assisted professor in providing a curriculum for undergraduate students regarding the styles of communication between people in businesses

Didi Hirsch Community Mental Health Center 11/2012 - 09/2013

Bilingual Therapist I

 Provided crisis intervention & facilitated conflict resolution. Provided intensive, short- and long-term individual and family therapy with children, adolescents, and adults diagnosed with a variety of disorders, using a variety of theoretical perspectives. Developed training curricula for new therapists and regularly taught workshops on psychology theories and best practices. Assessed other therapists' reporting and effectiveness

Performed intake assessments, client evaluations, and provided diagnoses; formulated a plan of treatment to promote development and maintenance of individual goals designed to facilitate individual growth, improved social interaction, ability to manage mental illness and live independently. Regularly assessed and monitored condition of client to evaluate success of treatment and adapted interventions as needed

Provided comprehensive case management to include referral and links to community support services, psychiatrist, medical care, housing, and social activity groups

Interfaced and collaborated with clinic psychiatrist regarding client treatment planning

 Monitored and maintained documentation of client services, ensuring compliance with Agency policies and procedures, DMH contract and other related agencies standards and guidelines

• Five Acres Boys & Girls Club 09/2011 - 06/2012

Bilingual Resident Therapist - Provided individual and family therapy for clients ranging from age 6 to 14. Created behavior management curriculum for children based on goals of increasing their frustration tolerance, developing anger management techniques and finding positive coping skills to implement in school & home environments ---- --- Collaborated with team members, parents, social workers, psychiatrists, and school staff to improve client care for all clients

• Freelance 02/2010 - 05/2013 Independent Workshop Teacher

- Taught domestic violence workshops for court-mandated clients Created curriculum and taught short-term and long-term classes on a variety of psychology topics. Hosted seminars for undergraduate psychology students

Hathaway-Sycamores Child & Family Services 08/2009 - 06/2011

School-Based Therapist/Wraparound Clinician

Provided community individual and family therapy for children and adolescents with diverse ethnic, socioeconomic, and disability backgrounds, in a school and home setting

Certified in Seeking Safety & Managing Adaptive Practices (MAP), Worked in a team setting with other therapists that included providing group therapy to clients

- Completed intake assessments, as well as creating therapy goals for all clients
- Worked in a team setting and attended Child Family Therapy meetings, school meetings and case consultations Prepared court letters and coordination plans for the Department of Mental Health

• Family Service Agency of Burbank 08/2007 - 12/2008 Lead Therapist

Provided individual, couple, family and group Psychotherapy, Facilitated support and focus groups, worked with children on building their self-esteem, self confidence, resolving family, individual conflicts and struggles

• Daylight Adult Day Health Care Center 11/2006 - 08/2009 Medical Social Worker

Taught workshops on positive coping skills and lifestyle improvement techniques based on clinical psychology best practices. Provided case management and one-on-one counseling for elderly clients. Built collaborative relationships with County Social Workers, written up reassessment reports, quarterly reports, provided needed community resources for all clients. Assisted clients with SSI application, CAPI and Section 8 housing application

Languages

Fluent in English, French, and Armenian

Skills

Strong written and oral communication, Excellent interpersonal skills. Strong ability to multi-task, prioritize tasks.

Strong ability to develop and teach curricula based on psychological principles and practices

Proficient in Client Management software

challenging circumstances. Experienced in Crisis Intervention

Ability to lead and act as key educator Apple and PC proficient; familiar with school online grading and testing platforms (Blackboard and others).